hello I'm your host David Barnard
today's conversation is shorter than
usual and will be featured in Revenue
cat state of subscription apps report
each episode in this series will explore
one crucial metric and share actionable
insights from Top subscription app
operators with me today Dimitri gersi
CEO and co-founder of flow Health on the
podcast I talk with Dimitri about why
the Big Mac index fails for app pricing
how Spotify and Netflix are Paving the
way for subscriptions globally and while
lower prices may be the key to unlocking
profitable user acquisition in Emerging
Markets hey Dimitri thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast today hello D
thank you for inviting I'm really
excited to talk to you specifically
about Regional pricing it's something
we're going to be sharing stats on in
the 2025 stateus subcription apps report
and it's something I don't think many
apps have really cracked but flow is one
of the few apps I've seen that does a
really good job at Regional pricing so
at a high level how do you think about
it what has kind of guided your strategy
for regional pricing around the world
there are several principles my first
statement will be that it's not right to
use very simplistic approach like for
example like a mark index or for example
to use pricing of Netflix or Spotify in
most of cases it would not work and for
example why it would not work in case of
of ma index when you're comparing like
cost of burger in United States is cost
of burger in Brazil the main reason that
you have very different audience like
different customers for burger and
potentially for your app I may predict
that average buyer customer of burger in
Brazil is just like average person in
Brazil but average customer of your
subcription in Brazil probably is a more
like more effluent part of society and
probably you iOS device rather than
Android device and because of that price
may be much higher than your big market
index like would predict almost always
prices originally are lower than United
States but there is like a huge
difference between approach pricing for
iOS for Apple devices and for Android if
you compare like Optimal pric and for
IOS and Android in rich countries like
United Kingdom for example or United
States like
Android is always cheaper almost always
cheaper how not so much cheaper maybe
20% cheaper maybe 15% cheaper regions
like Brazil difference in optimal
pricing may be huge because richer part
of society use iOS devices and because
of that propensity to pay and even
ability to pay is extremely different
between this categories of users in
English speaking world and worldwide and
because of that the pricing for IOS and
Android originally may have very big
difference in comparison with IOS and
Android in United States or in English
speaking world as a larger app you get
to do a ton of experimentation even in
some of these countries I think that is
a struggle for a lot of apps is that
they don't have the volume how do you
think about actually testing these
prices and how do you run those tests
and then how do you evaluate the winner
they have like a luxury have huge
audience and we have huge audience
worldwide like four is the biggest
Health app in the world and we have
maybe more than 200,000 installs daily
and of course having such audience and
having 70 million mon diffusers
worldwide we may afford like making ton
of experiments and because of that and
like we may make such experiments just
like using like kind of brutal force
approach just like to create enough
testing group like to put many prices to
test you compare with the initial price
and make a decision for each region but
very significant moment she consider
that we not measuring pricing and
success in pricing by conversions and
it's very often a big mistake we measure
pricing by influence on average revenue
per user and why because price is
correlated with many other metrics
conversion rate to trial then activation
in trial then retention of subscription
depends sign ific anly on cost we have
situation when price may be
significantly cheaper for example twice
cheaper but then retention is Three
Times Higher and overall rpu will be
much higher and because of that we are
making decisions not based on price in s
for conversion but based on influence on
rpu do you have any specific examples of
countries where you did do price
experimentation and like what the
results of that price experimentation
was on Revenue the got quite significant
success in Brazil this year and
significant means that Revenue was
growing like hundreds of per or year to
year very significantly and now Brazil
is a number three market for us for so
maybe market number four significant
Market really significant market and
what happened we reduced price
significantly really significantly and
it helped not just uh increase
conversions and improve retentions but
also what was the result we didn't
expect it unlocked P user acquisition
because with this price conversions are
enough to provide enough signals to
networks and to get the traffic
profitably like we found like a hot spot
for p acquisition with this price and
the increased volume of P acquisition in
Brazil very profitably significantly
this year because of that and it would
not be possible with higher prices just
because like level of conversions is not
enough like to really start wiing
auctions it's such a counterintuitive
thing but in a country like Brazil where
the ad inventory is so cheap then the
lower prices and the lower prices giving
a decent bump in conversion actually
makes it work so that's fascinating I'm
going to go out on a limb and propose
that subscription apps across the entire
industry should instead of using the Big
Mac index they should be using the flow
index given how much price testing
you've done do you think that your
pricing and your strategy and I would
say like percentages so if if us is the
index of one and then your Brazil pric
is2 and your Mexico pric is.3 and your
Germany pric is8 you know that would be
kind of the flow index of pricing do you
think the pricing works very
specifically for flow or do you think
that what you've learned about pricing
might be even more broadly applicable to
the industry recently which we compared
our prices of inlow with like average
prices in health and fitness category
and not even in absolute numbers but
more kind of relatively to United States
and I would say that it's pretty much
correlated but there are
exceptions and mostly this exceptions
maybe not so much about the country
itself maybe more about what apps are
popular and age distribution in this
apps because Flo naturally has mostly
users younger than 35 and other heals
they significantly sell subscriptions to
people older than 45 and then the
demographic and distribution of Android
and iOS May influence like average price
a lot and because of that I would not
advise to use any index or any Benchmark
because optimal price May depends on
many parameters like age of your users
platform type of product cultural
specifics and it just must be tested
that's really fantastic advice and the
cumulative effect of this approach is
that Flo seems to be doing much better
outside the US than a lot of
subscription apps I mean so many apps I
talk to are so dependent on the US and
make almost nothing in other countries
what does that look like for flow what
percentage of Revenue or how are you
doing outside the US compared to inside
it's true and
our International Revenue is growing and
even this grow is speeding up for
example this year we like Revenue out of
Rich English speaking Vault increased
like almost 80% and English speaking
Vault was 35% and mix was like something
like 45% of Revenue growth this year but
my prediction that long term FL will
even more money originally than in
United States and not even like in
English speaking world because I Al like
Australia Canada United Kingdom like
behave pretty much the same as United
States and now we have maybe 70% of our
revenue from this kind of English
speaking VA like what is traditional
source of money for subcription
companies but regions are growing very
fast and it's much more cultural
phenomenon than anything else and I have
a hypothesis that it's pretty much
driven by efforts of each subcription
businesses like Spotify and Netflix
because we see that uh when Spotify
Netflix and apple when they double down
on specific market for example Germany
or then Brazil then several years after
people there start to pay for FL
subscription or other subscriptions just
because they get in this habit they
acceptance that it's okay to pay for
digital subscriptions and there are
plenty of regions where people have
decent income for example Italy or
Poland and conversions to sub are really
low and not just for FL but for all
companies and again not just because
people there can't pay it's because of
cultural acceptance of the idea itself
that it's okay to pay for digital
products yeah that's fascinating the
last thing I wanted to talk to you about
was flow is doing something really
different than I've seen any other app
do and that's that you're offering a
completely free version in a lot of
countries tell me about why you're doing
that and how that's playing out we
believe that Flo is a very valuable very
useful product and me just don't believe
we have many scientific research to
prove that and we just think that it's
not right to blocks so useful product
behind pay wall in countries where women
just can't pay because of different
reasons because in some regions they
just don't have credit card or they just
don't have money all together and
conversions to subscriptions would be
really low and 99% or even more of our
users would not have access to the most
useful features and because of our
mission we decided that it's better if
you just open that for free and hundreds
of million women worldwide will be able
to become healthier and get knowledge
because of FLW and up to this moment we
have given more than 20 million
subscriptions like 20 million
subscriptions we gifted more
subscriptions than we
because like now we have 6 million
active subscribers maybe this like CH
maybe I don't know maybe we have sold 10
million or so but we have given 20
million and 20 million women worldwide
in poor countries they may use floor for
free and there not like a business here
it's like our idea that if you are doing
something good then when people may pay
they should pay but when the people
can't pay it's almost kind of sinful to
hide the product behind payable and
because of that flow is for free in uh
more than 50 countries wow that's
incredible and a great way to align the
mission are there learnings that do help
is there data coming from those users or
or other things that do help Propel the
business or is it just fully kind of a
charity oh it's the just charity you're
not getting any business value from that
like we're getting business value in
sense that our employees are more
motivated because Flo is good company
and our users more motivated because of
that and we inform that like they are
doing this Pro social campaign but there
is no like a direct business value like
I don't know like additional revenue or
some additional growth we would get
because of that no it's just like kind
of because of our mission and our desire
not just in money but also that to be a
good company and improve this
that's fantastic I don't know how many
other apps are so Mission driven that
they' be willing to do that but I think
it's incredible I mean for other apps
there may even be things like they could
do Tom's Shoes kind of made this famous
of like you buy a pair and then a pair
is donated maybe some apps could even
experiment with that even if they aren't
quite as generous a mission trim as as
you and the flow team are but I think
it's an incredible place to wrap up
aligning the mission and giving away
value for free to those who can't afford
and not getting business value out of it
is it's really an incredible thing it's
something I commend you for but as we
wrap up anything else you want to share
with the audience very interesting
moment she built subscription apps and
she built Health apps and all business
model has started working really well
and it was difficult to imagine that
apps would become like businesses with
hundreds of million in Revenue several
years back and next year Flo will earn
close to 300 million if you're
successful and it's the biggest Health
app in the world with
703 million month selective users and in
United States 25% of all women younger
than 45 are month selective users of
course we are Hing and I believe that
the quality of the team is the main
source of success let's look on our open
positions on our website or in LinkedIn
and please apply I'll share links to
your careers page and Linkedin in the
show notes so those of you who were
inspired by this conversation I want to
work for one of the coolest biggest
subscription apps in the world take a
look in the show notes and Demitri thank
you so much this has been such a
fascinating conversation I'll have to
have you back we had pages and pages of
notes that we could have talked about
we'll have to do a podcast later in the
year and really dive into more of your
learnings because you've learned so much
and shared so much and I really
appreciate it thank you much thank you
for inviting
me thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community